responsys.net 2007-03-10

# Responsys

Your Web Site Privacy Rights

**Effective Date: August 31, 2004**  
Responsys makes the same firm commitment to privacy for our web site visitors as we deliver to customers using our web-hosted service, Responsys Interact®. Responsys is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for [www.responsys.com](http://www.responsys.com/).

Responsys abides by the principles set forth in the Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

For privacy questions related to an email message you may have received from a company using Responsys Interact, please see our permission marketing policy/FAQ.

**TRUSTe Privacy Program**  
Responsys is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, nonprofit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this web site has agreed to notify you of: 

  * What personally identifiable information of yours (or third party personally identifiable information) is collected from you through the web site
  * The organization collecting the information
  * How the information is used
  * With whom the information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under Responsys' control
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our Privacy Advocate by email at [privacyweb@responsys.com](mailto:privacyweb@responsys.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the web site to resolve your concerns.

**Information Tracked**  
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our web site. We also track browser types to help us understand our visitors' needs related to our web site design.

Our site's optional information request forms such as White Paper Requests and Newsletter signup require your name, company, email address, and other information to help us determine your needs related to our solution. We use this information to send updates about our company and to contact you if requested or necessary. You may opt out of receiving future mailings; see the Updating and Choice/Opt-Out section below. When you receive an updated profile form, that information comes from our database.

**Security and Privacy**  
Responsys' web site uses security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We store the information in a database in a secure environment at our service provider, Savvis Communications.

Client-side cookies are used to verify the login status of customers using products or services linked directly with our web site. Client-side cookies are also used to track point of entry to point of registration for those users participating in our affiliate signup programs or to track and measure the success of a particular marketing campaign. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site; however, the user may be limited in the access to some areas within our web site.

Responsys takes care to reinforce the importance of our web site visitors' security and privacy among our employees. The bottom line is that, because our business involves hosting application accounts, data security is paramount. We're constantly reevaluating and deploying new technologies to enhance our security.

We will not share, sell, or rent individual personal information with anyone without your advance permission or unless ordered by a court of law. Information submitted to us is available only to employees managing this information for purposes of contacting you or sending you email based on your requesting information.

Responsys is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other web sites to which we link.

**Notification of Privacy Policy Changes**  
Responsys will notify its users of any changes to how Responsys uses personal information via email, with the new policy posted on the site at least 30 days prior to its effective date.

**Updating and Choice/Opt-Out**  
Visitors who request information on our web site have the following options for updating their profiles and unsubscribing (opting out) to avoid receiving future communications from us: 

  * Sending an email message to [privacyweb@responsys.com](mailto:privacyweb@responsys.com). We'll reply within 30 days of receiving your request confirming any corrections or updates requested.
  * If you are subscribed to receive newsletter or commercial emails from us, you may send us a request to unsubscribe from receiving such emails at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions within the email. We will comply with your unsubscribe request within 10 business days after receipt of such request.

If Responsys does not respond to your inquiry, or if your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>.

**Contacting Us**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement or this web site, please contact us directly:

Responsys, Inc.  
3 Lagoon Drive, Suite 300  
Redwood City, CA 94065  
United States  
650-801-7430

| Permission Marketing Policy | | | Privacy Policy | | | © 1998-2020 Responsys  
---|---|---|---|---
